Elkin Rodriguez

Software Developer

I'm a Software Developer passionate about code optimization and performance tuning for exceptional user experiences. I got solid knowledge in Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Search Engine Optimization (SEO), debugging code, algorithms and Data Structures. Furthermore, I have been specializing in User Experience to design and develop functional applications to achieve the highest quality of the delivered product. Also, I have strong communication skills, adaptability and problem-solving mindset.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

January 2023 - June 2023

Nub 7/8, Bogota, COL

- Create Mock-ups and Prototypes of application and new interfaces on
- Write functional, reusable and secure code according to best practices standards
- QA testing and debug code

Technologies | JavaScript | TypeScript | React | Material UI | Redux | JSON | SQL | Git & GitLab | Jira | AWS | Figma

Software Developer

January 2021 - December 2022

Tap4Click, Bogota, COL

- Create Mock-ups and Prototypes of application and new interfaces on
- Write functional, reusable and secure code according to best practices standards
- Build APIs to connect interfaces with Databases.
- QA testing and debug code

Technologies | JavaScript | TypeScript | React | Bootstrap | Tailwind | Material UI | NodeJS | Express | RESTful API | JSON | SQL | NoSQL | Git & GitHub | Jira | AWS

EDUCATION

Software Development

October 2020 - Today

PLATZI, Online

Certifications:

- Professional course on Git & GitHub
- Professional course on Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- React Professional Course
- Professional course on Databases (RDBMS NoSQL)
- APIs Fundamentals

Technical degree

January 2011 - December 2013

ECCI, Bogota, COL Software Development

CONTACT

- Open to Remote)
- +57-305-814-7854
- M elkinrodriguez03@gmail.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/elkinrodriguezs/ https://portfolio-website-liart-one.vercel.app/
- www.github.com/Elkinrodriguez03

SKILLS

Languages:

- Spanish (Native)
- English (Advanced)

Programming languages & Frameworks:

- · HTML5
- · CSS SASS SCSS
- · Bootstrap5
- · Tailwind CSS
- Material UI
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- · RESTful API
- · ReactJS
- AngularJS
- Node.JS
- NextJS
- Redux · JSON
- · SQL

Development Tools:

- · VS Code
- · Git
- · GitHub
- Docker
- Postman
- Jira
- · AWS Services

Design Tools:

- Figma
- · Adobe XD
- Overflow
- Miro

Team-Work Methodology:

Scrum